Hugo Gonçalves



Profile

Software Engineer with over eight years of dedicated experience in crafting distributed, real-time and high-performance backend systems.

Contact details

@ email@hugogoncalves.pt

* +351 91 00 41 754

github.com/goncah

hugogoncalves.pt

in linkedin.com/in/goncalh

orcid.org/0009-0007-5803-44<u>99</u>

Personal information

Citizenship: Portuguese

Languages: **Portuguese** (native),

English

Skills

- Java, Java EE, Jakarta EE
- Apache Kafka, Kafka Streams, Kafka Connect, AWS MSK
- Springboot, Helidon
- Wildfly

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER at *Vodafone Group.* **2024.05—present** \diamond Real-time payments fraud detection with Kafka, Kafka Streams and Java 21,

Charging & Payments integration with Springboot microservices.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER at *Vodafone Group.* **2023.04–2024-04**

 \diamond Ticketing, Inventory and Network Management systems integration API development with Java 17, Jakarta EE, Wildfly.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER at Vodafone Group. 2018.07–2023-03

 \diamond Workflow process development with Java 8 for the mobile network automation platform.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER at *Vodafone Group.* **2016.06–2018-06**

 \diamond Workflow process development with Perl for the Ericsson mobile network automation platform (FMX).

NETWORK ENGINEER at *Vodafone Group.* 2015.02–2018-06 \diamond 2^{2nd} level Ericsson mobile network configuration and support.

NETWORK ENGINEER at Vodafone Group. 2012.11–2015-01

♦ 1st level Ericsson mobile network configuration and support.

Network Engineer at Nokia Networks. 2011.12–2012-11

♦ 1st level Ericsson mobile network configuration and support.

NETWORK ENGINEER at Portugal Telecom. 2010.11–2011-11

♦ 1st level Ericsson fixed network configuration and support.

EDUCATION

MASTER'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND WEB TECHNOLOGY. Universidade Aberta. 2024—present

BACHELOR'S DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE.

Universidade Aberta. 2021–2024

HIGH SCHOOL DIPLOMA, INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY.

Escola Técnica e Profissional de Mafra. 2007–2010

RESEARCH

Gonçalves, H., & Shirley, P. (2024). Concurrent Binary Search Tree. *Revista de Ciências Da Computação*, *Vol. 19*, 71–86. https://doi.org/10.34627/rcc.v19i0.314